Did everything go okay with the annulment?
手續辦得還順利嗎？
No problems. It's all taken care of.
沒問題，都辦好了
Ross,thank you.
羅斯，謝謝你
Want to go see a movie?
你們要不要去看電影
Yeah,why not?
好啊
I'll get my sweater.
我去穿毛衣 好
Want to hear something weird?
想不想聽一件奇怪的事？
Always.
當然
I didn't get the annulment.
我沒去辦註銷
What?
什麼？
We're still married.
我們還是夫妻
Don't tell Rachel. See you later.
不要告訴瑞秋，待會見
Do you have any gum?
你有口香糖嗎？
Wait! Wait! Ross,can I just talk to you for just a second?
等等！ 羅斯，可以跟你談一下嗎？
We'll be late for the movie.
但是電影快開演了
There's a cab. Taxi!
那裡有計程車，計程車
That's great.
What timing! My God,huh? There you go.
來得正好，上車吧
We're gonna walk. It's right at the Angelika.
我們要走去前面的安潔麗戲院
The Angelika! Go! Go!
安潔麗戲院，開車
You didn't get the annulment?!
你沒去註銷？
I know.
我知道
I tried,but when I got to my lawyer's office, all I heard was:
我試過，但在律師樓我只聽到
"Three divorces! Three divorces!"
「離婚三次，離婚三次」
Yes,in that high voice.
沒錯，是女高音
I just don't want my tombstone to read: "Ross Geller: Three Divorces."
我不希望我的墓碑上刻著 「羅斯蓋勒，離婚三次」
Don't worry about that. Your tombstone can say whatever you want.
你不必擔心那個 你愛刻什麼就刻什麼
It can say, "Ross Geller: Good at Marriage."
你可以刻 「羅斯蓋勒，婚姻高手」
You know? Mine's gonna say, "Phoebe Buffay: Buried Alive."
我的會刻 「菲比布非，活埋在此」
All I know is,I can't have another failed marriage.
反正我不能再添一次失敗婚姻
So you're gonna be married to a girl who doesn't even know about it?
所以你要娶個不知情的女生？
Woman. Sorry.
女人，抱歉
Okay,so I don't have it all worked out quite yet.
我還沒想好要怎麼做
Just don't say anything to Rachel.
拜託你先別告訴瑞秋
Rachel is one of my closest friends.
瑞秋是我最要好的朋友之一
But being the only one that knows about this makes me feel special. Okay.
不過當唯一知情的人感覺不賴 好吧
Okay,stop,stop! Phoebe?
停車 菲比？
Hey,Rach!
瑞秋
What was that?
你在搞什麼？
Sorry. Mix-up.
抱歉，弄錯了
How was the movie?
電影好看嗎？
I haven't seen it yet.
我還沒看
You'd better hurry. The Angelika! Go!
那就要快了 安潔麗戲院，開車
不…
The One Where Ross Hugs Rachel
本集播出：「瑞秋的反應」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
When I move in, can I get a gumball machine?
等我們同居 我可以買一台泡泡糖機嗎？
Of course. Joey wouldn't let you have one?
當然可以，喬伊不讓你買？
No, when it comes to sweets, he's surprisingly strict.
對，他對甜食要求特別嚴
Did you tell him you're moving out?
你想好要怎麼說了嗎？
No,I keep trying. And I can get out,"Joey,I have to.."
還沒，我試了好幾次 我只能說出「喬伊，我得…」
Then I lose my nerve and I finish with, "go to the bathroom."
然後就退縮改說「去上廁所」
He may think I'm sick.
他可能以為我有病
I have to tell Rachel,but.... We just gotta get it over with.
我真的得告訴瑞秋了 早死早超生
Next time we see them, we'll just tell them. That's it.
下次見到他們，我們就說
That's how it'll work now? You'll just order me around?
就這麼決定 以後你都要這樣指使我是吧？
-Pretty much. -All right.
差不多 好
Hey,man,you feeling better?
摩妮卡 你有沒有好一點？
We have something to tell you.
喬伊，我們有事要說
Oh,my God!
天哪
You're pregnant!
你懷孕了
No!
不是
沒有吧？不是
Look, Joe,here's the thing.
喬伊，是這樣的
Monica and I have decided to live together, here.
摩妮卡和我決定在這裡同居
I'm gonna be moving out, man.
所以我會搬出來
I'm really happy for you guys. Congratulations. See you later.
我真替你們高興 恭喜，回見
Are you okay?
等等，喬伊，你還好嗎？
I gotta go. I've got an acting job.
很好，我得走了，我有戲要演
Like you'd believe that.
你們會信才怪
This sucks!
討厭啦
I'll be across the hall. And I promise you...
我只是要搬到對門，我保證
the minute Monica and I break up, I'm moving right back in.
摩妮卡和我一分手 我就回去跟你住
Maybe that's now.
你是說現在嗎？
If you're gonna move in with him...
好，如果你要跟他住
I feel it is my responsibility to tell you the truth about him.
我有責任揭穿他的真面目
He's a terrible roommate. Terrible.
他是個很爛的室友
He forgets to....
他會忘記…
He always,he always....
他老是…
Who am I kidding? He's the best roommate!
我騙誰啊，他最棒了
-Hey,Phoebe. -Hey.
菲比
Oh, look, here's an article about people who marry people and don't tell them.
有一篇文章在討論 結了婚卻不告訴對方的人
-Really? -Yeah, I'm reading Ross Geller Magazine.
真的？ 對，我在看羅斯蓋勒雜誌
Have you seen Rachel?
菲比，你有看到瑞秋嗎？
-No, why? -I have some exciting news.
沒有，怎樣？ 我有個好消息
You're pregnant.
你懷孕了
No!
不是
Chandler and I are moving in together.
錢德和我決定同居
Oh,that's good!
太好了
But if you were pregnant, what would you name it?  Hint,Phoebe.
不過如果你有寶寶要叫什麼？ 提示：菲比
What's up?
怎麼樣？
Chandler and I are moving in together.
錢德和我要住在一起
Oh,my God.
天哪
Oh,my little sister and my best friend...
我妹妹和我的死黨…
shacking up.
搞在一起
That's great. That's great.
太好了
Guys, I'm happy too.
喂，我也很高興
Okay,come here.
好，一起來
Big day,huh? People moving in. People getting annulled.
今天真熱鬧 有人要同居，有人辦註銷
I gotta go find Rachel.
我要去找瑞秋了，不過…
If you see her,give her some really bad news, so mine doesn't seem so bad.
你們能不能先灌些壞消息給她 減輕一些衝擊？
再見
Something bad to tell Rachel.
講給瑞秋聽的壞消息…
Bad news for Rachel. What could that be?
什麼是她的壞消息？
Can you just lay off, please?
你能不能別再提了？
My life is an embarrassment. I should just go live under somebody's stairs.
我的人生很難堪 我應該去住在別人的樓梯底下
It's not that big a deal. You'll have been divorced three times.
根本沒那麼嚴重 離婚三次又怎樣
You'll have a life,you'll date..
你還是會有私生活、會約會…
No, I won't. I'll be at the bottom of the dating barrel now.
才不會 我的約會指數降到谷底
The only guys below me will be Four-Divorce Guy...
比我低的只有離婚四次的人
Murderer Guy...
殺人犯和…
and geologists.
地質學家
Ross, you're being ridiculous. You are cute and smart and sweet.
羅斯，你別傻了 你可愛聰明又體帖
That is much more important than three stupid divorces.
這比離婚三次重要多了
Have you dated anyone who's been divorced three times?
是嗎？ 你交過離婚三次的男朋友嗎？
That's not fair. Most guys that have been divorced three times are 60.
這樣問不公平 離三次婚的人通常都60了
You're young.
你多年輕啊
That's true,I am young.
我是很年輕
Well....
Nobody cares about this except you.
只有你自己在意
This embarrassment thing is all in your head.
什麼難堪都是你在想像
-Here,I'll show you. Come here. -What?
我證明給你看 過來 幹嘛？
Hi. My friend Ross is about to be divorced for the third time.
我朋友羅斯即將三度離婚
But wouldn't you date him?
但你們會和他約會吧？
And if you wait right here, I'll go get Ross.
你們稍候，我去找羅斯來
Thought you were Rachel.
我還以為你是瑞秋
What gave me away?
我哪裡露出破綻了？
I gotta tell her.
我得趕快告訴她
I told Ross and Phoebe. She's the only one left.
我已經告訴羅斯和菲比 只剩她了
It's official. We're moving in together.
所以大家都知道了 我們確定要同居了
No turning back. Are you scared? Are you?!
不能反悔 你怕嗎？怕嗎？
No.
不怕
That was my scariest voice. You're brave.
那是我最可怕的聲音 你真勇敢
The worst day.
今天真慘
You're finally making progress at work, then your boss calls you Racquel.
你以為自己終於受重視了 結果老闆卻叫你拉蔻兒
Listen,for the first four years of my work, everybody called me....
我進公司前4年 大家都叫我夏拉拉
-Seriously. -I believe you.
是真的 我相信
It was in the middle of a meeting, so no one wants to correct her.
當時正在開員工大會 當然不會有人糾正她
So everyone's calling me Racquel.
於是大家都叫我拉蔻兒
By the end of the day,the mailroom guys were calling me Rocky.
到了下班前 收發室的人已經叫成洛基了
Well,I still think you're very,very nice and very pretty.
我還是覺得你很好很漂亮
What?
什麼？
All yours, babe.
交給你了
瑞秋，過來
Have a seat.
坐
Listen,Chandler and I...
聽我說 錢德和我...
are going to live together.
要一起住在...
Here.
這裡
Oh,my God.
天哪
That's so great!
真是太棒了
I'm so happy for you guys!
我真替你們高興
Really?
真的？
And that was so sweet of you to ask.
你真好，還先問我
The three of us are gonna have such a good time living together!
天哪 我們三個在一起一定會很開心
Yes,we are.
是啊
Chandler, you'll have to watch those long showers you take...
錢德，你早上不能慢慢沖澡了
because you know Racquel can't be late.
因為拉蔻兒不能遲到
He'll work on that.
瑞秋 他會注意的
This is so exciting!
好興奮喔
Come and knock on our door
來敲我的門 （影集「三人行」主題曲）
We'll be waiting for you
我們等著你
See? Once you know the stories, it's not that bad.
一旦知道內情就沒那麼糟了
First marriage: Wife's hidden sexuality. Not my fault.
第一次，老婆隱瞞性向 不是我的錯
Second marriage: Said the wrong name at the altar.
第二次，宣誓時叫錯人
A little my fault.
有一點點是我的錯
Third marriage: They shouldn't let you get married...
第三次 怎麼能讓...
when you're drunk and have writing on your face.
臉上塗鴉的醉鬼結婚
Nevada's fault.
內華達州的錯
So what do you think, ladies? Who wouldn't want to date him?
你們覺得怎樣？誰會沒興趣？ 誰會不想和他約會？
The divorces don't bother me. I'd date him.
離婚無所謂，我會和他約會
But not while he's still married.
但他得先恢復自由身
And you,wouldn't you want to date?
那你呢？你也想吧？
I'm not dating at all anymore.
事實上我再也不約會了
I was only dating guys that were bad for me.
我老是看上對我不好的男人
So I decided that..
在我解決這個…
Good. Good. Whatever.
隨便啦
And you,Meg?
梅格你呢？
Well,I don't care about the divorces, either.
我也不在意離婚的事
But I wouldn't date him.
但我不會和他約會
Normally, he doesn't sweat this much.
他平常不會流這麼多汗
It's just that he's obviously still in love with this Rachel girl.
他顯然還愛著這個瑞秋
What?
什麼？
She said,"He's obviously still in love with this Rachel girl."
她說 「他顯然還愛著這個瑞秋」
This is crazy. I mean, yes, Rachel is my good friend.
這話太扯了 沒錯，瑞秋是我的好朋友
And I have loved her in the past...
我過去確實愛過她
but now, she is just my wife.
但現在她只是我的妻子
Phoebe, will you help me out here?
菲比，幫我說句話好嗎？
Well, I thought you loved her when you married her.
你娶她時我也以為你愛她
We were drunk! I would've married Joey with that amount of alcohol.
我們喝醉了 喝那麼多我連喬伊都會娶
You could do a lot worse than Joey Tribbiani!
比喬伊崔比亞尼爛的人多得是
I'm sorry, but you guys are wrong.
很抱歉，但是你們錯了
I just don't want to be divorced three times.
我只是不想離三次婚
Now he's using this three-divorces reason...
沒錯，他以此為藉口...
because he wants to stay married to her because he loves her.
不想離婚 因為他愛她
I must say, well done. Bravo,Meg.
我必須說：梅格，幹得好
Fine. If this is what you think, forget about...
好，如果你們這麼想
the whole three-divorce thing.
那我就不管了
I'll go to my lawyer's office right now and get this marriage annulled.
我現在就去找律師辦註銷
She means nothing to me.
因為我一點也不愛她
Nothing!
一點也不愛
Okay, now I wouldn't date you because you seem a little creepy.
現在是你的神經質讓我發毛
I am so attracted to him right now.
我突然覺得他好有魅力
When will we tell Rachel what actually will happen?
我們什麼時候要跟瑞秋說實話
Soon.
快了
I just couldn't before. You saw how upset Joey got.
我剛才說不出口 你也看到喬伊多難過
I couldn't do it. She's my best friend.
我不忍心傷害我最好的朋友
Joey's my best friend.
喬伊也是我最好的朋友
I'm not your best friend?
我不是嗎？
You just said..
你自己剛才說…
Of course you're my best friend.
你當然是
Would you tell Rachel?
但請你告訴瑞秋好嗎？
All right. At least I'm prepared.
好啦，至少我現在有準備 好
Oh,yes.
漂亮
-They're not for you. Are you upset? -I am now.
不是給你的，你有不開心嗎？ 現在有了
Hey,roomie.
室友
Okay,bye.
好，再見
There's something important I have to tell you.
瑞秋，我有重要的事要告訴你
Are you pregnant?
你懷孕了？
No, but I'm throwing this shirt away.
沒有，但我要扔掉這件衣服
I think there was a little misunderstanding before.
剛才有一些誤會
When I said that Chandler and I wanted to live together...
我說錢德和我想住在一起
we meant alone together.
意思是只有我們兩個人
Oh,my God. That's funny. I can't believe I did that.
天哪，真好笑，我居然會誤會
No, sweetie. You know what? This is my fault.
不，是我不好
I wasn't clear.
我沒說清楚
I'm really sorry.
真的很抱歉
Listen,you take as much time as you need to move out, okay?
你可以慢慢找房子
There's absolutely no rush.
一點也不用急
Okay.
好
Don't you want a cookie?
你不吃餅乾嗎？
Sure.
好啊
Thanks.
謝謝
Do you need a tissue?
需要面紙嗎？
-Where did you get these? -I made them.
這是哪裡的餅乾？ 我做的
Oh, God, they're so yummy!
天哪，真好吃
-Okay, whose is this? -That's mine.
這是誰的？ 我的
-And what about this? Whose is this? -That's mine.
那這個呢？ 也是我的
Okay, whose dishwashing soap is this?
那這罐洗碗精呢？
That was here when we moved in.
我們搬進來時就有了
Oh,I guess it really is concentrated.
難怪濃成這樣
It's gonna be weird when I come home and you're not here.
以後我回家你就不在了
No more Joey and Chan's.
沒有喬伊和錢德家了
No more J and C's.
沒有喬和錢家了
Want to go to Joey and Chandler's? Can't. It's not there.
「要不要去喬伊和錢德家？」 「不行，已經不在了」
I'll be across the hall. We can still do all the same stuff.
我只是搬到對面 我們還是可以跟以前一樣
We won't be able to have those long talks at night...
但以後就不能半夜起來
about our feelings and the future.
促膝長談感覺和未來了
Not once did we do that.
我們一次也沒做過
Don't you remember that night, it was late and I was feeling sick...
不是有一次很晚了，我不舒服
and you said I would feel better tomorrow?
你說我「明天」就會好一點？
Oh, yeah. I remember that.
對，我記得
I don't know. I'm just gonna miss living with you.
我會想念那些事
Yeah,me too,man.
我也是
-What the hell is that? -That's disgusting.
那是什麼？ 好噁心
I told Rachel that it's just gonna be the two of us.
我告訴瑞秋我們要自己住了
Oh,yeah? Well,how'd she take it?
是嗎？她還好嗎？
Really well.
非常好
Surprisingly well.
令人意外的好
She didn't cry. She wasn't angry or sad.
沒有哭，也沒有生氣或難過
And you're upset because you didn't make your best friend cry?
你很不爽沒把手帕交弄哭？
All I'm asking for is a little emotion.
我只求一點真情流露
Is that too much to ask after six years?
我們6年室友耶
What,are Rachel and l not as close as you guys?
我們沒你們要好嗎？
I mean,did we not have as much fun? Don't I deserve a few tears?
沒你們開心嗎？ 我不值得她掉幾滴淚嗎？
When we told Joey, he cried his eyes out.
喬伊一聽到就哭得死去活來
I did not cry my eyes out!
我才沒有哭得死去活來
Come on, it's like the end of an era.
這就像一個時代的結束
No more J-Man and Channy's!
再也沒有喬兄和錢哥了
Okay,I gotta ask,who calls us that?
我一定要問 有誰那樣叫我們？
You got married again?
你又結婚了
Yes.
對
So that's your second marriage in two years?
這是你2年內第二次結婚
Yes. Second in two years.
對，2年兩次
Third,overall.
總共三次
I have been a divorce attorney for 23 years...
羅斯，我當了23年離婚律師
and never have I had so much business from one client.
沒有一個客戶比你捧場
Why don't you tell me what happened?
告訴我怎麼回事
Basically,Rachel and I were in Vegas,a nd we got drunk.
基本上，瑞秋和我在賭城 我們喝醉了…
I'm sorry, is this the same Rachel whose name you said...
抱歉，她就是你上次結婚
at the altar in the second marriage?
叫錯的那個瑞秋？
Yes,yes,yes.
對
But I do not love her.
但是我並不愛她
That's better then.
這就好多了
This was just a drunken mistake, and I need to get it annulled.
這只是酒醉犯錯，我要辦註銷
I see.
我懂了
Have you considered therapy?
你考慮過接受治療嗎？
I think just the annulment for today.
我想今天辦註銷就好了
-There are some forms to fill out. -Easy.
要填幾份表格 簡單
We'll need witnesses who can testify that you were not of sound mind.
必須有證人證明 你們當時神智不清
No problem.
沒問題
We'll need you and Rachel to testify before a judge.
你和瑞秋得向法官說明
There's no way to do this without her?
不能不找她嗎？
Because I kind of already told her it was taken care of.
我已經告訴她事情都辦妥了
Of course you did.
你當然這麼說
Look, you can't get an annulment unless you and Rachel are both there.
羅斯，你和瑞秋都在場 才能辦理註銷
What about someone who looks like Rachel?
那找一個長得像瑞秋的人呢？
I will think about the therapy.
我會考慮接受治療
So I was thinking that maybe we should start dividing up our stuff.
我想我們應該開始分東西了
Okay.
好
No point in dragging it out.
沒必要拖拖拉拉的
Dragging out the long process of you moving out...
我是說你搬走
and us not living together anymore.
我們分開的事
好
What about this? Who gets this?
瑞秋，這個要歸誰？
I don't know if I want it because it might be too many memories.
我不知道我想不想要 它有太多回憶
-What is that? -I don't know.
那是什麼？ 我不知道
How about this? I want you to have the big plate.
瑞秋，大盤子呢？ 我要你留著大盤子
Wow, Monica, thanks. I love this plate.
謝謝，我很喜歡這個盤子
Something to remember me by.
這樣你就會記得我
Mon, you're not dying. I'm just moving out.
你又不是快死了 我只是要搬出去
We're gonna see each other all the time.
我們還是會天天見面
But still,it's a big change.
但這是個大轉變
The end of an era, you might say.
甚至是一個時代的結束
Are you okay? You're not blinking.
你還好嗎？眼睛都沒眨
I'm fine. I was thinking about how it's an end of an era.
我很好 我只是在想一個時代要結束了
Oh,all right.
好吧
But I gotta say, I don't think six years counts as an era.
但老實說 6年應該稱不上一個時代
An era is defined as a significant period of time.
一個時代就是一段重要的日子
It was significant for me. Maybe it wasn't significant to you!
我覺得重要 或許你不覺得重要
-What is the matter with you? -What is the matter with you?!
你是怎麼了？ 你才怎麼了？
Why aren't you more upset?
你為什麼沒有更不開心？
Aren't you gonna be sad that we're not living together?
我們要分開了你不難過嗎？
Aren't you gonna miss me at all?
你都不會想我嗎？
Monica, all right. But don't get mad at me.
好吧，說出來你別生氣
It's just a little hard to believe.
我只是有點難以相信
What's hard to believe?
難以相信什麼？
I mean,it's you guys. You do this kind of stuff,you know?
你們啊，你們就是這樣
You were gonna get married in Vegas, and then you backed out.
你們在賭城說要結婚又不結了
I'm not upset because I don't see you going through with it. I'm sorry.
我並不認為你們會真的同居 對不起
It's going to happen.
瑞秋，事情已經確定了
Chandler will move in here.
錢德會搬進來
-But I.. -I know,just let me finish, okay?
但是… 你先聽我說完
This isn't something that we just impulsively decided to do in Vegas.
這不是在賭城的一時衝動
This is something that we both really want.
我們真的想要住在一起
And it is going to happen.
我們會住在一起
It is?
是嗎？
Really?
真的？
Yeah,sweetie.
沒錯
You mean,we're not gonna live together anymore?
我們不能再住在一起了？
不行了
Oh,my God. I'm gonna miss you so much.
天哪，我會好想你
I'm gonna miss you.
我也是
I mean, it's the end of an era!
這是一個時代的結束
I know!
我知道
-Okay, bye. -Oh,no.
再見 又來了
So did you get the annulment?
你去辦註銷了嗎？
-I couldn't. -I knew it. Because you love Rachel.
我辦不了 我就知道，因為你愛瑞秋
It's not that. Annulments are more complicated..
不是那樣的 事情比想像中複雜…
Complicated because of the love.
愛讓它變得複雜
I do not love Rachel.
我不愛瑞秋
I'm telling her about the whole thing...
我現在就去告訴她
so we can get this marriage annulled as fast as possible.
好盡快把手續辦好
Would I do that if I loved her?
我如果愛她會這麼做嗎？
I've never been more convinced of your love for her.
我現在更確信你愛她
I do not have feelings for Rachel, okay?
我對瑞秋沒有感覺，好嗎？
Oh,what's wrong?
怎麼了？
Monica and Chandler are moving in here...
摩妮卡和錢德真的要同居了
and I have to move out and everything is changing.
我得搬出去，一切都要變了
Oh, my God, come here, come here. It's okay.
過來，別難過，不會有事的
Everything's gonna be okay.
不會有事的
-Thank you. -Of course.
謝謝你 不客氣
So Ross and Rachel got married.
羅斯和瑞秋結婚了
Monica and Chandler almost got married.
摩妮卡和錢德差點結婚
You think we should hook up?
我們要不要送做堆？
Oh,we do.
要
But not just yet.
但不是現在
Really? Well,when?
是嗎？那是什麼時候？
Well, first Chandler and Monica will get married...
好，首先錢德和摩妮卡會結婚
and be filthy rich,by the way.
還會發大財
But it won't work out.
但婚姻會破裂
I know.
天哪 是啊
Then I'll marry Chandler for the money.
然後我會為錢嫁給錢德
And you'll marry Rachel and have the beautiful kids.
你會娶瑞秋生幾個漂亮小孩
Great.
太好了
But then we ditch them and we get married.
接著我們就拋棄他們結婚
We'll have Chandler's money and Rachel's kids.
我們會有錢德的財產 瑞秋的孩子
Getting custody will be easy because of Rachel's drinking problem.
監護權很好搶，因為瑞秋酗酒
What about Ross?
那羅斯呢？
I don't want to go into the whole thing.
我不想多說，不過…
But we have words and I kill him.
我們吵架，我殺了他